skysports.com 2018-12-31

# Sky Privacy and Cookies Notice | Sky Help | Sky.com

  * Information you've provided to us, including through our websites or when you access our services through applications on websites operated by other organisations.

  * Information about our content, products and services you've ordered or enquired about, including call recordings, as further described below.

  * Information provided to us by other organisations, such as address verification services (e.g. Royal Mail in the UK) and data brokers (e.g. Experian) and credit reference agencies; this includes personal data that is publicly available.

  * Information, uploads, user generated content, and comments you make about, or generate, in accessing the shows, channels, programmes, advertisements, products and services you use, for example, how you or your household access, view, share, contribute to, communicate with, record or fast forward them.

  * Information we collect, via cookies and related technology, from the devices or viewing cards you use to receive Sky content, products and services, about your and your household’s use of Sky, and/or third party content, products and services. This includes information about your device, machine or browser which can be collected when cookies are turned off. For more information on cookies and how to manage them, please see the section on cookies.

  * IP address, MAC address, unique identification number, online identifier, browser information, location data port information, logical network address, and other similar identifying information required for your devices to communicate with websites and applications on the internet.

  * Technical information from the devices you use to receive Sky content, products and services, for example, the collection of diagnostic and traffic or location information. Note that devices and applications have their own privacy settings and notices under which they collect your information, so please check and manage your device and application settings.

The main purpose for which we process your personal data is so that we can, in accordance with the contract you have with us, provide you with content, products and services. This includes, where the contract requires it, for example: providing you with account management functionality (such as to update contact information), customer support (including diagnostics and trouble-shooting), call screening and blocking, and tailored and personalised recommendations.

In order to enter into loan agreements with you, we obtain personal data about you from credit reference agencies. We then take automated decisions using that personal data about whether or not to enter into the loan agreement with you. This decision is influenced by your credit history and, depending on the outcome of this automated decision making process, we may not enter into the loan agreement with you. If you would like us to review decisions taken about you as part of this process, please contact us as set out below. 

In addition, we also use your personal data for the following legitimate business purposes:

  * Managing our products and services and traffic across our network. For example, Sky uses your information to facilitate the operation of its network by choosing the most efficient route to transmit your requests for a communications service through the various parts of its network of equipment and systems. This information is held securely within restricted areas, accessible only by authorised personnel and in accordance with our data retention, deletion and acceptable use policies.

  * Improving our content, products, services and customer experiences by monitoring your use of our products and services and working with our suppliers to improve the products and services we offer, and develop new content, products and services.

  * Monitoring, recording, storing and using customer service communications we have with you. This helps us to improve the quality of our customer service, to confirm any instructions you give us, to create a customer profile to have better conversations and/or for training, development and to meet our legal and regulatory responsibilities.

  * Showing adverts to the people most likely to be interested in the products and services being promoted. To do this, we create a profile about you which we use to define groups of audiences to whom we send adverts, based on factors like interests, age, location and more. As part of showing these adverts, we also carry out quality and frequency checks, such as whether adverts were displayed correctly and how often particular adverts have been shown. 

  * For market research.

  * Protecting or enforcing our rights or the rights of any third party such as by analysing activity on our network to help block unauthorised or illegitimate content, publication of, or access to it.

  * Safeguarding an individual’s vital interests.

  * Complying with our legal and regulatory obligations (for example, in the context of police investigations and national security).

We work with a number of suppliers to process your personal data for the purposes described above. These suppliers act on our behalf and must only process your personal data in accordance with our instructions. The categories of suppliers that we use include:

  * Engineer services firms 
  * Couriers
  * IT companies
  * Customer service centres
  * Service providers who work with us to allow us to meet our obligations as a listed entity
  * Other Sky group companies (Information can be found [here](https://www.skygroup.sky/corporate/about-sky))
  * Marketing companies that deliver our communications

Where our suppliers are based outside of the European Economic Area (for example we use customer service centres in India and some IT services in USA), we grant these suppliers access to personal data only if appropriate measures and controls are in place to protect your personal data in accordance with applicable data protection laws, regulations and regulatory guidance. More information can be obtained about this processing by contacting us as described in this notice. 

One of Sky’s data processors (Domestic & General Insurance PLC and Domestic & General Services Limited) may contact you to ensure you are satisfied with your service experience and to let you know about the warranties that apply to your Sky equipment and the options for extended cover. 

In the event the structure of our business changes so that another company in the Sky group provides our products and services to you, we will pass your personal information to that company. This includes, for example, a merger between us and another company, where another company acquires us or some or all of our assets, where we acquire another company or where our holding company restructures our corporate group.

We share your personal data with credit reference (e.g, Equifax) and fraud prevention agencies (eg CIFAS) for use in automated credit decisions, for the detection and protection against crimes such as fraud and money laundering, and for debt recovery purposes, as further explained below. If, from the information you have provide, fraud is identified, details will be passed to fraud prevention agencies to prevent fraud and money laundering. We and other organisations may access and use, from other countries, the information recorded by fraud prevention agencies. Please contact us (by selecting **yes** to the question at the bottom of the page) if you want to receive details of the relevant fraud prevention agencies and further details explaining how the information held by fraud prevention agencies may be used.

We share personal data with the courts, enforcement agencies (e.g. the police) and with regulatory authorities (e.g., OFCOM in the UK) where this is required, in order for us to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations.

We work with a number of trusted partners to process your personal data for online and digital advertising purposes. This includes data like your IP address and device ID, which are required to serve advertisements to your device. We will never share your name, physical address or phone numbers with any of our trusted partners. 

We perform due diligence before a company becomes a trusted partner and is able to handle your data in a secure and responsible manner. This processing is based on your acceptance of cookies on our website and your Sky ID preferences. The categories of partner that we work with include:

  * Advertising agencies and advertisers, which buy advertising on Sky’s online and digital platforms so they can deliver targeted and tailored advertising and can measure which advertisements are clicked and other such results associated with displaying such advertisements; and

  * Advertising platforms (e.g. Google, Rubicon, Unruly and Outbrain) which help Sky to deliver tailored and targeted advertising across Sky’s online and digital platforms. These advertising platforms enable Sky to offer its advertising space and manage use of that advertising space efficiently.

Where our partners are based outside of the European Economic Area, we work with these partners to make sure personal data is processed only if appropriate measures and controls are in place to protect your personal data in accordance with applicable data protection laws and regulations and regulatory guidance. More information can be obtained about this processing by contacting us as described in this notice.

**Unless you've asked us not to (see below), we may also use your information on the basis of your consent, contract for service or our legitimate interest:**

  * To provide you with more relevant advertising and tailored offers (including discounts). Sky can serve different ads to groups of people and to different Sky households, customers or individuals within a household watching the same programme or service. We use the information you have provided to us or information we have collected about you and your household to tailor the adverts you receive and make them more relevant, by playing an advert on your TV or device when the relevant audience may be most likely to be watching.

  * To send you direct marketing. This may include communications by post, telephone, SMS, email or other electronic means, using the contact details you have provided, about us and our content products and services, events and special offers, including, for a reasonable time after you have ceased to be a customer of ours (see further details below).

  * To send you newsletters about your service, content and relevant products.

You can contact us via your [Manage account](https://www.sky.com/manage/my-details) or [My Account](https://account.nowtv.com/account-details) on Now TV or on 03442 414 141 (in the UK) or 0818 719 819 (in ROI) to update, amend, correct your information. You also have the following rights: 

  * To request access to, or erasure of, the personal data we hold about you.
  * To request us to restrict the processing of the personal data we hold about you.
  * To object to us processing personal data relating to you.
  * Where you have given us consent to process your personal data, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time.
  * You have the right to obtain certain personal data from us in a format that can be transferred electronically to a third party (also called “data portability”).

Please note that some of these rights are not absolute. In some cases, we may refuse a request to exercise particular rights if complying with it meant that we are no longer able to meet our contractual obligation to provide you with particular products and services. However, we will keep you informed as to the actions that we can take, when you make your request. 

**Direct marketing and tailored advertising**

You can always choose not to receive direct marketing or tailored advertising from us in the following ways: 

  * Via your [Manage Account](https://www.sky.com/mysky/my-details) in My Sky or [My account](https://account.nowtv.com/account-details) for Now TV
  * Clicking on the "unsubscribe" link in any electronic marketing information from us
  * Calling Sky on 03442 414 141 (in the UK) or 0818 719 819 (in ROI) for Sky TV, BB & Talk
  * Emailing: [optout@nowtv.com](mailto:optout@nowtv.com) for Now TV
  * Emailing: [preferences@nowtv.com](mailto:preferences@nowtv.com) for Now TV

You can choose not to receive direct marketing from any other Sky group companies by contacting them directly. 

**Cookies and online behavioural advertising**

Please see the section on "Controlling my Cookies" on how to adjust cookie settings for your devices. 

Cookies are small bits of text that are downloaded to the devices you use to receive Sky content, products and services and access online information. Your browser makes these cookies available every time you visit the website again, so it can recognise you and can then tailor what you see on your device.

Cookies are an important part of the internet. They make using devices and accessing online information much smoother and affect lots of the useful features of websites. There are many different uses for cookies, but they fall into four main groups.

**Cookies that are needed to provide the content, product or service you have asked for**

Some cookies are essential to help your devices download or stream the information, or so you can move around websites and use their features. Without these cookies, content, products or services you've asked for can't be provided. 

Here are some examples of essential cookies:

  * Positioning information on a smartphone screen, tablet device or other screen so that you can see the website and use its functionality.
  * Keeping you logged in during your visit or enabling you to stream content. Without cookies, you might have to log in on every website you visit, or repeatedly adjust your volume and viewing settings.
  * When you add something to the online shopping basket, cookies make sure it's still there when you get to the checkout.
  * Some are session cookies which make it possible to navigate through the website smoothly.

**Improving your browsing experience**

Cookies allow the application or website to remember choices you make, such as your language or region, and they provide improved features.

Here are a few examples of some of the ways that cookies are used to improve your experience on our applications and websites:

  * Remembering your preferences and settings, including marketing preferences, such as choosing whether you wish to receive marketing information.
  * Remembering if you've filled in a survey, so you're not asked to do it again.
  * Remembering if you've been to the application or website before.
  * Restricting the number of times you're shown a particular advertisement. This is sometimes called 'frequency capping'.
  * Showing you information that's relevant to content, products or services that you receive.
  * Giving you access to content provided by social-media sites like Facebook or Twitter.
  * Showing 'related article' links that are relevant to the information you're looking at.
  * Remembering an application or website you've entered, such as weather forecasts.

**Analytics**

We like to keep track of what websites, information and links are popular and which ones don't get used so much, to help us keep our information relevant and up to date. It's also very useful to be able to identify trends of how people navigate (find their way through) our information and when and where 'error messages' may originate.

This group of cookies, often called 'analytics cookies', are used to gather this information. The information collected is grouped with the information from everyone else’s cookies. We can then see the overall patterns of usage rather than any one person’s activity. Analytics cookies are used to improve how an application, a website and its pages work.

Our applications, web locations, websites and communications you get from us contain small invisible images known as 'web beacons' or ' pixels'. These are used to manage the interaction between you and the online information or email and allow us to assess the effectiveness of the communication.

**Affiliate cookies**

We use 'affiliate' cookies. Some of our web based information will contain promotional links to other companies’ sites. If you follow one of these links and then register with or buy something from that other site, a cookie is used to tell the other site that you came from one of our sites. That other site may then pay us a small amount for the successful referral. For more information, see the [Internet Advertising Bureau's](http://www.iab-performance-marketing-explained.net/) guide about how affiliate marketing works. Note that when you visit those other companies’ sites, they will have their own privacy notices which set out what personal data they collect and how they will use it.

We sell space on some of our websites, mobile sites and apps to advertisers. The resulting adverts often contain cookies and related technology that is placed by trusted third party partners who use the browsing information collected from these cookies to:

  * Restrict the number of times you see the same ad (frequency capping) and

  * Help show other advertisements that are relevant to you while you're accessing our information. This information about your browsing activity may be grouped with information about what is being accessed by other users, into interest groups, and then used to show you advertisements based on those interests. This is often called online behavioural advertising (OBA). OBA is a way of using information about your web-browsing activity, collected by using cookies, to group you with other users into interest groups and show you advertisements based on those interests.

Sometimes our websites contain advertisements for our own Sky products. These advertisements use cookies in the same way as described above. We may also use cookies and related technology on third party websites, mobile sites and apps to show you OBA ads based on data collected by those cookies.

If you want to know about data collected by third parties when you click on their adverts, you should check their privacy notices to find out what they collect, how they process it and what they use it for.

It’s easy to choose not to receive behavioural advertising and manage your cookies, if you want to.

 **How can I see and manage my cookies in my browser?**

Virtually all modern browsers allow you to see what cookies you've got, and to clear them individually or clear all of them. To find out how to do this, go to [aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/), which contains comprehensive information on how to do this on a wide variety of desktop browsers.

**How can I choose not to receive Online Behavioural Advertising and other tracking cookies?**

In addition to the controls available on your computer, there are other ways of choosing not to receive Online Behavioural Advertising and other tracking cookies.

Please note that most of these choices work by setting a cookie that overrides the behavioural advertising cookie. If you clear all your cookies, you will also clear these opt-out cookies, therefore changing your preferences. In this instance you would need to choose again.

**Organisations which provide more information on Online Behavioural Advertising**

  * [Evidon](http://www.evidon.com/consumers-privacy/manage-your-online-profile) is a provider of privacy solutions. 

  * [Internet Advertising Bureau (IAB)](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices) “Your Online Choices” page allows you to choose not to receive behavioural advertising from each of the advertising networks represented by the IAB. 

  * [Network Advertising Initiative (NAI)](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) opt out page allows you to choose not to receive behavioural advertising from each of the ad networks represented by the NAI.

  * [Digital Advertising Alliance’s](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) self-regulatory program for online behavioural advertising choices page.
